为什么我总是出力
Why do I always have to carry the heavy stuff?
很简单啊
Well, it's very simple.
在我们这群一无所有的破烂科学家当中
In our ragtag band of scientists with nothing to lose,
我负责动脑子
I'm the smart one,
沃罗威茨负责搞笑
Wolowitz is the funny one,
库萨帕里是一个奋力想要融入我们的生活
and Koothrappali is the lovable foreigner
但是以失败告终的可爱的老外
who struggles to understand our ways and fails.
你别无选择  只有肌肉男了
That leaves you, by default, as the muscle.
再多搬一层  我就肌肉难了
One more floor, and I'd be the pulled muscle.
来的正好 我要饿死了
Oh, it's about time. I'm starving.
这个  其实我们没带中国菜回来
Um, well, we didn't actually get Chinese food.
-为什么啊  -淡定 这个更赞
- Why not?  - Don't panic. This is better.
不是吧 你们不会用食物换了魔豆吧
Oh, no. You didn't trade the food for magic beans, did you?
当然没有
Of course not.
况且严格来说  魔豆也是食物
And technically, magic beans would be food.
虽然吃了它们怪浪费的
Although eating them would be quite a waste,
因为你可以种植它们
since you could plant them,
然后一夜之间  就会长成一株巨大的豆茎
and overnight, have a giant beanstalk,
足够一个小城市吃的
which would provide enough roughage for a small city.
其实有时候我根本没听你说话
Yeah, sometimes I don't listen.
只是看着你的下巴一上一下
Sometimes I just watch your jaw go up and down.
我们去中餐馆的路上
We were on our way to the Chinese restaurant
貌似看见了亚当·韦斯特
when we thought we saw Adam West,
（亚当·韦斯特:《蝙蝠侠》的扮演者）
所以我们就跟着他走
so we followed him.
谁是亚当·韦斯特
Who's Adam West?
Who's Adam West?!
莱纳德  你们性交之后都聊些什么啊
Leonard, what do the two of you talk about after the coitus?
我猜是  "哇塞  4分钟  新纪录啊"
My guess is, "Hey, four minutes! New record!"
所以我才负责搞笑啊
That's why I'm the funny one.
反正呢  我们跟着他到了旧货出售摊儿
Anyway, we followed the guy to this garage sale,
那卖的东西都超赞
and they had the coolest stuff.
他们正好关门大甩卖
They were closing up.
这一箱子东西才60块
We got this whole box for 60 bucks.
我们还没来得及看清都有什么呢
We didn't even get to go through it all.
说不定有什么宝贝呢
There could be anything in here.
看看有没有新女朋友 说不定你需要一个
There a new girlfriend in there? 'Cause you might need one.
没有
No.
不过有《捉鬼敢死队》的原版终稿
But there is an original final draft Ghostbusters script
上面真的有黏液的污迹哎
with actual slime stains!
你说得对
Oh, you're right.
这个是《捉鬼敢死队2》
It's Ghostbusters 2.
没看头
Never mind.
我滴神啊
Oh, my God.
是阿福娃娃
An Alf doll.
我11岁时  我妈在我爸去世后
When I was 11, my mother got me one
给我买了一个 让我能睡好觉
to help me sleep after my dad left.
我那时候会假装 爸爸是去了蜜胺树脂星球
I used to pretend that my dad had moved to the planet Melmac,
而阿福会把他带回我身边的
and Alf was going to bring him back to me.
但它从来也没有
But he never did.
我爸爸在哪儿  小玩偶
Where's my daddy, puppet?
他在哪儿
Where is he?
太伤感了
That is so sad.
不  更伤感的是你居然不知道
No, what's sad is that you don't know
亚当·韦斯特是电视版蝙蝠侠的扮演者
Adam West was TV's Batman.
生活大爆炸第三季第十七集
史波克的脑袋(波克:《星际迷航》中的人物)
Here's Spock's head with no body.
T先生的身子(Mr.T:《星际迷航》中的人物)
Here's Mr.T's body with no head.
啊在这儿  史波克的身子配T先生的脑袋
Oh, yeah, here's Spock's body with Mr.T's head.
我同情那些没有逻辑的傻瓜
I pity the fool who's illogical.
好吧  我要回家了
Okay, I'm just gonna go home
做一个烤干酪  然后上eHarmony 意淫去
and make a grilled cheese and window-shop on eHarmony.
（eHarmony:美国线上交友网站）
好的  拜拜
Okay, bye.
妥了
Okay.
哇塞  快看  《夺宝奇兵》的连连看
Ooh, look, an Indiana Jones connect-the-dots.
还有潜水侠的手办
And an Aquaman action figure.
好像有人给他画了个小弟弟
Looks like someone drew a penis on him.
没事儿  看我擦掉
Ooh, that'll come off.
我们都看不下去了喂
You see what you're doing?
停下
Stop that.
真赞啊
Fascinating.
什么东西
What?
是《魔戒》里的魔戒
It appears to be a Lord of the Rings ring.
上面居然还刻着
Oh. It's even got
精灵语呢
the Elvish engraving on it.
不是精灵语
It's not Elvish.
是用精灵语的字母写的魔多语
It's the language of Mordor written in Elvish script.
"魔戒全属至尊御"
"One Ring to rule them all."
（出自《魔戒》台词）
"至尊指引诸魔戒"
"One Ring to find them."
"至尊魔戒唤众戒"
"One Ring to bring them all."
"众戒归一黑暗中"
"And in the darkness bind them."
我靠  咱们好宅啊
Holy crap, are we nerdy.
我调查了一下这个魔戒
So, I was doing some checking on the ring.
等下  谢尔顿  那边桌子上的是番茄酱吗
Hold on. Sheldon, is there ketchup on that table?
是滴
Yes, there is.
有个好玩的事儿 起初 番茄酱是酱汁的总称
Oh, here's a fun fact. Ketchup started out as a general term for sauce,
特别是那些加了草本植物和香料的 蘑菇或腌鱼
typically made of mushrooms or fish brine with herbs and spices.
早期流行的主材料包括蓝莓
Some popular early main ingredients included blueberry,
凤尾鱼  牡蛎  四季豆  还有葡萄
anchovy, oyster, kidney bean and grape.
没事儿  我去拿
No, that's okay. I'll get it.
听我说  我仔细观察了魔戒 看上去有点奇怪
Listen, I was looking at the ring, and it seemed a little weird.
上面竟然没有版权声明
No copyright notice on it.
所以我就拿给我一个哥们儿看  这么说吧
So, I took it down to this buddy of mine who deals with--
他专门和收藏界的黑市 做交易
shall we say-- the seedy underbelly of the collectibles world.
黑市
Seedy underbelly?
你那个黑市淘来的手提式相位枪
You know, your black market phasers,
（出自《星际迷航》）
还有乌拉中尉在电影中穿过的内裤
your screen-worn Lieutenant Uhura panties,
就那些东西呗
that kind of stuff.
你这个神秘兄弟是谁
Who's this mysterious buddy you suddenly have?
就是我认识的一个家伙
Just a guy. I know a guy.
-艾迪·克里斯波吗  -我不能告诉你  别问了
- Is it Eddie Crispo? - No, I can't tell you who it is. Stop asking.
还能是谁  肯定是艾迪·克里斯波
Who else could it be? It has to be Eddie Crispo.
我认识很多黑道人物  好不好
I know lots of dangerous people, okay?
-说一个  -艾迪·克里斯波
- Name one. - Eddie Crispo.
不管怎样 他说这个不是仿品 而是真品
Anyway, he said this isn't a replica. It's the real deal.
如果你说这就是索伦在末日火山
If you're suggesting that that is the actual ring of power
打造的至尊魔戒[指环王情节]
forged by Sauron in Mount Doom,
我会用极为不屑和
I look at you with an expression of exhaustion
嘲笑的表情看着你
and ever so slight amusement.
他不是说这是魔戒
He's not saying it's a magic ring.
对吧
You're not, are you?
没错  但差不多
No, but it's close.
看里面的标记
Look at the markings inside.
那是生产标记
Those are production markings.
为拍摄《指环王》  共打造了九枚戒指
Nine rings were made for use in the Lord of the Rings movies.
三枚送给了剧中演员
Three were given to members of the cast.
剩下的都被销毁了
The rest were destroyed.
除了一枚
Except one.
被偷的一枚
One was stolen.
先生们
Gentlemen...
这就是至尊魔戒
this is the one ring.
归我了
Mine!
不  不是你的
No, it is not yours.
我们一起去要的箱子
We all went in on the box together.
对  但是我在箱子里找到的
Well, yes, but I found it in the box,
海难救助法明确规定
and the laws of maritime salvage clearly state
找到沉海宝藏的人
that the finder of a sunken treasure
即视为宝藏的主人
is the owner of the treasure.
这怎么符合海难救助法
How is this maritime salvage?
除了没有水  怎么不符合
Other than the lack of water, how is it not?
等等  谢尔顿  先别发疯
Wait, wait. Sheldon, stop being crazy for a second.
这种东西值多少钱
How much is something like this worth?
这么抢手的东西很难估价
Well, it's tough to say since it's hot,
不过在黑市里  我朋友估价
but on the underground market, my guy figures...
你是指艾迪·克里斯波吧
Your guy Eddie Crispo?
是滴
Yes.
他估价一万到一万五
He figures ten, maybe 15 thousand.
既然值这么多钱
Okay, that's a lot of money.
明智之举是用它投资更实用的东西
The wise thing to do is invest it in something practical.
比如水上摩托艇
Like a jet ski.
你要摩托艇干嘛
Why do you want a jet ski?
电影里有钱又帅的人都骑摩托艇
All the wealthy and beautiful people in movies ride Jet Skis.
这不可能是巧合
That can't just be a coincidence.
我们不能卖它
We can't sell it.
要保存它
We have to keep it
珍惜它  爱护它
and love it and polish it,
只能偶尔拿出来
and only take it out occasionally
去公园里
when we go to the park
重演电影里喜欢的场景
and reenact our favorite scenes from the movies.
听着有意思  其实很无聊
It's sad how great that sounds.
各位  这是偷来的
Guys, it's stolen.
应该还给彼得·杰克逊[指环王导演]
It should go back to Peter Jackson.
他制作的电影  魔戒应该属于他
He made the movies; it belongs to him.
行啊
Fine.
可以换给他  只要他答应
He can have it back as long as he promises
让我演下一部电影里的霍比特人
to make me a hobbit in his next movie.
没有犹太霍比特人
There are no Jewish hobbits.
显然你没在岁首节[犹太新年]
Clearly, you've never been to my house
来我家吃饭
for dinner on Rosh Hashanah.
我们不能敲诈彼得·杰
We are not blackmailing Peter J...
够了  魔戒哪去了
All right, where's the ring?
你是说我的魔戒吗
You mean my ring?
你这是干嘛
What are you doing?
魔戒无人看护
The ring was unguarded.
就这么放着台面
It was just sitting on the table.
谁都能拿走
Anyone could have taken it.
证据  我拿了
Proof? I did.
-给我  -大家理智点
- Give me that. - Look, let's be reasonable.
我们都对魔戒抱有不同的想法
We all want to do different things with the ring,
但你们的想法太傻  我要的可是摩托艇
but your ideas are stupid, and I want a jet ski.
我找到的  魔戒是我的
I found it. The ring is mine.
我不明白  为啥每次都不能我说了算
I don't understand why in this group I never get my way.
有哪次不是你说了算
You always get your way.
你把魔戒给我  才是每次我说了算
I'll stipulate to that if you give me the ring.
各位
Hey, guys.
喜欢我给你们上的
Enjoying your food that I actually
不是你们点的菜
brought you instead of promising food,
是我随意找的一堆垃圾
but bringing you a box of random crap?
很好吃
Yeah, it's delicious.
就是讽刺的话不太新鲜
The sarcasm's a little stale, though.
要不这样吧
Hey, how about this?
确定如何处理魔戒前
Until we figure out what to do with the ring,
由佩妮来保管
Penny holds on to it.
什么戒指
What ring?
这枚戒指
This ring.
在找东西吗
Looking for something?
你能保管几天吗
Will you hold on to this for a couple of days?
-为什么  -这是部电影的道具
- Why? - It's a prop from a movie,
我们正为此争吵呢
And we're kind of fighting over it.
只想说清楚  我男朋友给我的
Okay, just to be clear, the first piece of jewelry
第一件珠宝是电影里的道具
my boyfriend gives me is a prop from a movie,
而且我还不能拥有它
and I don't even get to keep it?
如果你三年前跟了我
If you had gone out with me three years ago,
你现在应该能收到我姑婆艾达
by now, you'd have my great Aunt Ida's brooch
塞进猫肚子从德占比利时偷运出的胸针
that she smuggled out of occupied Belgium in a cat.
现在感觉我还好吧
How am I looking now?
你打我
You hit me!
我在流血
I'm bleeding!
什么情况
What was that?
谢尔顿想偷魔戒  我给了他一拳
Sheldon tried to take the ring and I punched him.
干得好
That's my girl.
谢尔顿啊
So, Sheldon,
被一个女人家揍的感觉如何
how's it feel to get beaten up by a girl?
反正不是第一次了
It's not the first time.
在子宫里我那胞姐就开始欺负我
I have a twin sister whose assaults began in utero.
如果当年我能一直坚定的吸收掉她
If only I'd had the presence of mind to reabsorb her,
我也就多了一颗长毛的痣
then I'd have a mole with hair in it
这样也不会收到那些无聊的圣诞贺卡了
instead of a tedious yearly Christmas letter.
先生们  你们还没有觉悟吗
Gentlemen, have you come to the realization
最明智的选择
that the only reasonable course of action
就是卖了魔戒再分钱
is to sell the ring and divide the money?
没门
No.
我就怕你这么说
I was afraid of that.
说吧
Go ahead.
在孟买问候大家
Greetings from Mumbai.
我是拉杰的律师  文卡塔斯·库萨帕里
I am Raj's attorney, Venkatesh Koothrappali.
也是我表哥
Also my cousin.
你居然还找了个律师
You brought a lawyer?
这个不用回答
Don't answer that.
我就直说了
I'll get straight to the point.
我的委托人准备放弃
My client's prepared to surrender
他在这枚魔戒上的一切利益
any interest he has in the ring
来交换两辆川崎水上摩托
in exchange for two Kawasaki Jet Skis.
两辆水上摩托是不可能的
We're not giving him two Jet Skis.
听着  大家都成年人了
Look, we're big boys,
我们何不都退一步海阔天空呢
why don't we just cut to the chase and meet in the middle?
一辆水上摩托就够了 怎么样
One Kawasaki Jet Ski. Done and done.
半辆都不给
No Jet Skis.
好吧  不谈水上摩托了
All right, forget the Jet Skis.
你说什么 这是我们的底线
Forget the Jet Skis? That was our line in the sand!
你就这点招数吗
What happened to "tear them a new one?"
那你要我怎样 他们态度强硬 我们输了
What can I say? They played hardball. We lost.
你这没用的东西
You're useless.
你来雇我时我就说了
I told you that when you hired me.
我要下线了
I'm signing off now.
记得联系你妈 她担心你呢
Call your mother. She worries.
知道吗 向别人介绍自己的律师表兄时
Okay, just so you know, if we're bringing in cousins who are lawyers,
要准备好被雷
prepare for shock and awe.
告诉你们  我来了结这件事
You know what? I am ending this.
佩妮不想再保管魔戒
Penny didn't want to hold the ring anymore.
她还给了我  现在我手上 我要寄回去
She gave it to me. I have it. I'm sending it back.
魔戒呢
Where's the ring?
你是指这个魔戒吗
You mean this ring?
下次在公共厕所里排尿
Next time be aware of your surroundings
记得要耳听八方环顾四周
while urinating in a public men's room.
快给我
Give me that.
才不  这是我的
No, it's mine.
我们都有份
It's all of ours.
-得了  这也太荒唐了  -那就放手
- Okay, now, this is ridiculous!  - Then let go!
偏不  你干嘛不放手
I'm not letting go. You let go.
要我说  谁坚持到最后
I say this ring belongs
魔戒就归谁
to the last person who can hold on.
行啊  我们回家再开始吗
Fine. But can't we go home and start this?
当然 那现在先放手
Sure. Let go of the ring.
好吧  那就从现在开始
All right, it starts now.
今晚科幻频道有巨虫电影联播
You do realize there's a giant bug movie marathon
你们都还记得吧
tonight on the Syfy Channel.
慢  我的笔记本还没拿
Wait, my laptop.
这也太白痴了  一点也没意义了
You know, there's a point no when this becomes idiotic.
刚我们这样开车的时候你咋不说
And it wasn't when we were driving like this?
我好心建议你们三个放弃吧
I would advise the three of you
再怎么死撑也是徒劳
that resistance is futile.
我的耐性可是出了名的好
I have endless patience.
我曾和惠普的客服人员
I once spent two-and-a-half hours on hold
耗了整整两个半小时
with Hewlett-Packard customer service
就为投诉他们客服态度差劲
just to complain about their customer service.
你少和我吹嘘耐性
You want to talk about endless patience?
佩妮逼我看完了整整
Penny made me watch all five seasons
五季的《欲望都市》
of Sex and the City.
老兄  那玩意有六季
There are six seasons, dude.
噢  杯具
Oh, crap!
别这么说嘛  第六季很赞啊
No, no, no, the sixth season is great.
凯莉刚分手  伤心地去了巴黎
We go to Paris with Carrie and get our heart broken,
而大人物又突然出现
and then Mr. Big shows up,
我们都很好奇  她是否还能再相信他
we don't know if we can trust him again.
真是跨越地球的爱恋啊
It's a wild ride.
我要开门
Door.
同志们  屈膝[法语 芭蕾舞动作]
Okay, everybody, and plie?
再踮立[法语 芭蕾舞动作]
And releve?
你们干什么呢
Whatcha doin'?
谁坚持到最后  魔戒归谁
Last one holding the ring decides its fate.
我知道这很蠢
I know, it sounds silly.
才不会呢  你是我男友啊
No, no, no, no, no, you are my boyfriend.
情人眼里出西施嘛
Nothing you do is silly to me.
多谢
Thank you.
顺便说下  这可是维多利亚的秘密内衣
FYI-- this is a bag from Victoria's Secret.
老子不干了
I'm out.
抱歉  老妈
I'm sorry, Ma,
没办法  我要在办公室加班
I have to stay late at the office.
才没有  他在骗你
No, he's doesn't! He's lying to you!
你就不能消停点吗
Will you be quiet?
要隐私的话  放开手就行了啊
Well, if you want privacy let go of the ring.
真开心
I'm so glad
终于能来这家异教徒的脱衣舞俱乐部
we came to this gentile strip club!
霍华德
Howard,
再给你个培根  塞她们丁字裤里去
here's more bacon to tuck into the shiksa's G-string!
我再打给你
I'll call you back.
你实在太贴心了  还特地打电话
I think it's lovely you call your mommy
告诉你妈  你赶不回去吃晚饭
and let her know you're going to be late for dinner.
据我所知
From what I know about these things,
没能按时喂奶的女人
if a woman doesn't breast-feed on time,
咪咪会很不舒服的
it's very uncomfortable for her boobies.
别跟我谈我妈的咪咪
Don't you talk about my mother's boobies!
听着不爽的话  放手啊
If you're offended, let go of the ring
赶紧回家找你妈吃奶去
and go on home to your mother's boobies.
太好了  太好了
Excellent, excellent.
你们俩耗吧  我就能笑到最后
Tire each other out, the ring will be mine.
霍华德  何不谈谈拉杰他妈
Howard, why don't you go after Raj's mother?
不然咱谈谈你妈
Why don't we go after your mother?
尽管谈
Go ahead.
我又没有恋母情结
I have no illusions about my mother.
她就一个和蔼可亲
She is a kind, loving,
笃信上帝  极端右翼的德州人
religiously fanatical right-wing Texan
头长得有点不合比例
with a slightly out-of-scale head
还对佩珀汽水有点上瘾
and a mild Dr. Pepper addiction.
还有什么要补充的吗
Anything you'd like to add?
这样说根本没用
That's not gonna get you anywhere.
得给他来点狠的
Better pull out the big gun.
说得对
You're right.
咱来谈谈你祖母
Let's talk about your grandmother.
不要
No!
不许说我奶奶
I call no Meemaws.
想想看
Think about this.
你奶奶肯定得跟人上床  才会有你妈
The only way your mother was born was your Meemaw had sex.
我不想听这些
I don't want to hear this.
那就放手  走一边去
Then let go of the ring and walk away.
想都别想
Never.
好吧
All right.
我敢说  你奶奶
I'll bet your Meemaw
不仅仅是为了传宗接代才跟人上床的
didn't just have sex to have your mother.
我敢说  她肯定也享受性爱
I bet she had sex because she liked it.
别说了
Stop it!
对  奶奶也并不圣洁
Yeah, Meemaw did the nasty.
我叫你们闭嘴
I said stop it!
说到他痛处了
We're getting to him.
瀑布
Waterfalls!
什么
What?
瀑布
Waterfalls.
惊涛拍岸
Crashing waves.
潺潺溪流
Babbling brooks.
你这是干嘛
What are you doing?
潜意识信息
Subliminal messaging.
通过这让你们产生尿意
I'm going to make you want to pee.
滴水的水龙头
Dripping faucets.
漏水的水槽
Leaky gutter.
尿尿
Peeing.
这招根本不管用  伙计
It's, it's not working, dude.
已经管用了
Oh-ho-ho, it's working all right.
我想上厕所
I have to pee.
那就放开魔戒去啊
Then let go of the ring and go.
其实  我也想上了
No, actually, I wouldn't mind going, too.
好吧
Fine.
数到三
Um, on the count of three.
一  二
One, two...
等等  先说清楚
Wait, just to clarify.
数到三  是都站起来还是直接尿尿
When you get to three, do we stand up or do we pee?
都站起来
We stand up.
明智之选
Excellent choice.
三
Three.
我有预感
Something tells me
今天真不该穿绒面革皮鞋的
this was a bad day to wear suede shoes.
我做到了
I've done it!
我赢了
I've won!
魔戒是我的了
The ring is mine!
是我的了
It's mine!
得彻底清洗下  让它更漂亮
We're going to clean it up and make it pretty.
是我的
My own.
我亲爱的
My love.
我的宝贝
My precious.
（谢尔顿华丽变身《魔戒》中的咕噜[Gollum]）
魔戒呢
Where's the ring?
在联邦快递的盒子里  回它原来的地方去了
It's in a FedEx box on its way back to where it came from.
（索伦在末日山的火焰中铸造了至尊魔戒）
末日山的火焰之中
The fires of Mount Doom?
彼得·杰克逊(《魔戒》导演)在新西兰的办公室
Peter Jackson's office in New Zealand.
本就不是我们的
It wasn't ours.
你早就退出了比赛
You quit the game!
根本没资格拿走魔戒
You had no right to take it.
我走进来的时候  你们都睡着了
I came in here, you guys were all sleeping.
魔戒掉在地板上  没人拿着
The ring was on the floor. No one was touching it.
那就该重新开始  直到产生最后的赢家
Well, so then we start the game over until there's a winner.
根本不会有什么赢家
There wasn't ever going to be a winner.
只会有一个手握魔戒的自私鬼
There was going to be a selfish, petty person with a ring
和三个反目的好友
and three people who used to be his friend.
你们真想这样吗
Is that really what you guys want?
真想的话  随便吧
'Cause if it is, fine.
我跟你们也没什么好说的了
I don't want anything to do with you.
还有  厕所里怎么回事我不知道
And I don't know what happened in that bathroom,
但我才不会去清理
but I am not cleaning it up!
我的宝贝
My precious.
我就知道
I knew it.
把宝贝还我们
Give us the precious!
-快给我  快给我  -放开我
- Give me! Give me! - Get off of me!
-把魔戒给我  -魔戒是我的
- Give me the ring! - It's mine!
真该跟健身房那笨蛋约会看看的
Ugh, gotta go back to dating dumb guys from the gym.
把魔戒给我
Just give me the ring!
Give it to me!
把魔戒给我
Give me the ring!
我让你给我
I said give it to me!
魔戒是我的
It's mine!